Hortense Kassoy Papers 6386
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Hortense Kassoy Papers
1975-2013
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kassoy, Hortense
6386
6.67 cubic feet
6.3 linear ft.
Papers.
8507561
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 07, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 27, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Hortense (Honey) Kassoy, who died at 96 on July 5, 2013, was an artist as adept with a chisel as she was with a paint brush.
Honey, as she was known to all, moved with her husband Bernard (Bernie) to the Amalgamate Houses in 1950 and they quickly became active members of the community.
Among the many activities Honey as she was known to all embraced were the Amalgamated Nursery School, the co-op's visual arts committee, the costume ball committee, a publication called Co-op Voices and the Apricot theater group. Her sculpture, "Maternal Force," is a permanent fixture in the courtyard of the two Amalgamated towers located on Sedgwick Avenue between Saxon and Dickenson avenues.
She was a teacher at Evander Childs High School and a founding member of the Bronx Council on the Arts who was instrumental in founding the Bronx Museum of the Arts.
Honey was corresponding secretary for the United Stats Committee of the International Association of Artists, a branch of UNESCO, from 1979 to 1993.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6385: Bernard Kassoy Papers 6385 F: Bernard Kassoy Films 6385 P: Bernard Kassoy Slides and Photographs 6386 P: Hortense Kassoy Slides and Photographs
8507561
- American Society of Contemporary Artists: Constitution and by-laws (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ASCA: Member Selection (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ASCA: Collapsed (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ASCA: Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 4)
- ASCA: 1988 Awards (Box 1, Folder 5)
- ASCA: 1993 Awards (Box 1, Folder 6)
- ASCA Activities Committee, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- ASCA: Letterhead (Box 1, Folder 8)
- ASCA, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- ASCA: General (1 of 2), 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- ASCA: General (2 of 2), 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- ASCA: Minutes, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- ASCA: Minutes, Handwritten, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- ASCA: General, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- ASCA: Minutes, Published, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- ASCA: Minutes, Handwritten, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- ASCA: General, 2000-2008 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- ASCA: Minutes, Published and Handwritten, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- ASCA: Exhibitions, 1981-2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- ASCA: 75th Anniversary, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- ASCA Membership Lists and Directories, 1981-2010 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- ASCA Newsletters, 2001-2005 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- ASCA Newsletters, 2005-2010 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- ASCA Pamphlets, 1993-2004 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- A.N.D. Alert, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Accounts Due, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Aging Study: Albert Einstein Collect, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Alfred University, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Archives of American Art, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Art Bank, 1962-1998 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Art Worker News, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Arts International, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Atelier Artistique International de Seguret, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Awards, 1978-2013 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Bernard Kassoy, 1946-2008 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Bills, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Bills for Art Supplies, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Biographical Material, 1983-2008 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Bocour, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Bonnzvalle, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Borax Council on the Arts, 1976-1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Borax Museum of the Arts, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- The Builders, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Butternut Hill, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Contemporary Artists Guild, 1978-1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Contemporary Artists Guild: Art is a Gift, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: Personal, 1964-2008 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Dance Routines (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Evander Childs High School, 1964-2008 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Febland School (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, 1999-2011 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Fine Arts Federation, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Forma Viva, Yugoslavia, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Galleries and Opportunities (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Gallery Exhibits, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Group 3, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Hesse Gallery Appraisal, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Honey's Credits, 1932-1947 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Hortense Kassoy (Box 2, Folder 15)
- International Association of Art, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- International Sculptors Conference, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- International Sculptor Conference, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- International Sculptors Conference, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Italy: Marbles, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Italy: Marbles, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Italy: Marbles and Bronzes, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Johnson Atelier Institute of Sculptors (Box 2, Folder 23)
- League of Present Day Artifacts, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Lehman College Courses, 1983-1999 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Lehman College Footnotes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Lists of Works (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Memorabilia, 1932-1946 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Meredith Kassoy (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Miscellaneous Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 30)
- NY Artists Equity, 1975-2008 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- NY Artist Equity Association Notebook, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Nancy Callahan, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- National Museum of Women in the Arts, 1986-1999 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Peabody Institute, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Photographer's Release, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Postcards and Greeting Cards, 1960-2003 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Potsdam Campus Art Tour, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Preparation for Pioneer Failure (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Price Lists; Sculptures and Basics (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Provenance and Certification of Authenticity (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Publicity, 1974-1989 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Radicals in the Bronx, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Retirement, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Resumes and Exhibits, 1992-2007 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Sculptors Guild, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Sculpture: Solo, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Sculpt World News (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Smithsonian, 1999-2002 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Tallix, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Teacher Observation Reports: Hortense Kassoy (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Teacher Observation Reports: Bernard Kassoy, 1946-1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Teachers College, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Teaching, 1947-1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Transcripts, 1936-1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- United Substitute Teachers, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- VAC Caf One (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Video: David Howard, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Virginia Center for the Creative Arts (1 of 2), 1987-2011 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Virginia Center for the Creative Arts (2 of 2), 1987-2011 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Voice, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Women in the Arts, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Women in the Arts, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Who's Who, 2003-2010 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Poetry and Other Writings (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Press Notices (1 of 2), 1980-2005 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Press Notices (2 of 2), 1980-2005 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Brochures, 1972-1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Brochures, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Exhibition Information, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Exhibit Information, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Exhibit Information, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Exhibit Information, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Exhibit Information, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Exhibit Information, 2002-2006 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Butternut Art Inventory (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Mercantile Library Association Exhibition (Box 4, Folder 2)
- New York Artist Equity Association Exhibit (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Yonkers Art Association Exhibit (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Art: USA, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- National Academy of Design, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Seventh Annual Eastern Frontier Art Exhibit, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Studio Exhibitions, 1963-1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Seventeenth Community Art Exhibition, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Mosholu-Montefiore, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Wayne Gallery, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- National Academy of Design Exhibition, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Ohio Dows Exhibit Guest Book, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Open the Gate Committee Exhibition, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Caravan Gallery Show, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Artist Equity Exhibitions, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Contemporary Artists Exhibition, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Core Gallery, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Artist Equity of New York, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Cork Gallery Exhibit, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Upper Catskills Exhibition, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Westlake Gallery, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Contemporary Artists Guild Exhibition, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Women in the Arts Exhibition, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Vladeck Hall, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Contemporary Artists Guild Exhibition, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Englewood Art Show, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Vladeck Hall, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Brotherhood Synagogue Exhibition, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- NCJW Exhibition, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Hudson Guild Art Gallery Exhibition, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Vladeck Exhibition, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Ward-Nasse Exhibit, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Ward-Nasse Exhibit Publicity, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Ward-Nasse Exhibit Guest Book, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Pioneer Gallery (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Hudson Guild, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- 80th Birthday Retrospective, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- 80th Birthday Exhibit Guest Book, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Smithy Pioneer, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- 85th Birthday Retrospective, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Smithy Pioneer Gallery, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Vladeck Hall, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Smithy-Pioneer Gallery, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Clippings, 1969-2011 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Travel Europe, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Travel Journal: Europe, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Travel Journal: Russia, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Travel Journal: Italy, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Travel Journal: Europe, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Travel: Colorado, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Travel: Poland, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Travel: Mediterranean Cruise, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Diaries, 1934-1945 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Diaries, 1946-1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Diaries, 1970-1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Passports and ID Cards, 1943-2011 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Notebooks (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Scrapbook, 1946-1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Scrapbook, 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Calendars, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Calendars, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Calendars, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Calendars, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Calendars, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Calendars, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Calendars, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Calendars, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Calendars, 1995-1998 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Sketch Book (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Sketchbook (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Oriole: Evander Child's High School, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Calendars, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Calendars, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Calendars, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Calendars, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Calendars, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Calendars, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Calendars, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Calendars, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Calendars, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Calendars, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Calendars, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Calendars, 2010-2012 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Posters, 1974-2002 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Sketch of Bernie (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Diplomas, 1928-1936 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Clippings, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)